Hester Lynch Piozzi Letters to Dr. William Makepeace Thackeray
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1812 November 24; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 22 x 18 cm. (Box [77])
  Piozzi discusses the expense of repairs to Streatham Park. She sent her steward to deliver her "Humiliations" to her daughters. Frost and wet have made a bad harvest. People mentioned: Bennet, Piozzi's daughters, Leak, and Salusbury.
  Correspondence; Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863 -- Correspondence; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821 -- Correspondence; Streatham Park (London, England)
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1813 January 7; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [78])
  Thackeray has asked for information on "Greatorex," whom he suspects "of having written Junius." Piozzi believes him to be one of "Lord Shelburne's Literary Retainers" and that Gerald Hamilton wrote "those famous letters." Piozzi mentions her amusing "story of a Stilton Cheese." She complains of her daughters' refusal to let her sell Streatham Park and of the cost of repairing it. She marvels that both she and Dr. Thackeray have lived to see the year 1813. People mentioned: Salusbury, Greatorex, Lord Shelburne, Gerald Hamilton, Mrs. Piozzi's daughters, Gabriel Piozzi, and Selina Thackeray.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1813 September 20; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 1 page (2 leaves): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [79])
  Comments on Salusbury's position as an orphan. Piozzi hopes he and Dr. Thackeray will become good friends. People mentioned: Piozzi's housekeeper, Piozzi's housekeeper's mother, and Salusbury.
  Correspondence; Piozzi, John Salusbury; Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863 -- Correspondence; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821 -- Correspondence
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1815 December 13; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 4 pages (2 leaves): autograph letter, signed; 24 x 19 cm. (Box [80])
  Piozzi hopes to visit Thackeray in July "unencumber'd by Debts & no longer haunted by Vexations which have tormented me for two long years." She has finished renovating Streatham Park. She is now in Bath, "Two Rooms & Two Maids her whole Establishment." She discusses visiting actors and dancers and mentions a ten year old who plays the piano "like a professor." Piozzi also copies out a short poem. People mentioned: Miss Letitia Barnston, Mrs. Salusbury, Dr. Holland, Dr. Harington, Mrs. Thackeray, and Selina Thackeray. See: Bloom, vol. 5, p. 433.
  Correspondence; Streatham Park (London, England); Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821 -- Correspondence; Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863 -- Correspondence
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1816 September 10; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 1 page (1 leaf): autograph letter; 19 x 12 cm. (Box [81])
  Piozzi has arrived in Chester and plans to go to Bath with Salusbury. She writes from the Jackson Hotel. People mentioned: Salusbury.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, between 1795 and 1816?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 3 pages (2 leaves): autograph letter; 24 x 19 cm. (Box [82])
  Piozzi copies out "A Song made in Time of the Mutiny by Desire of some Loyalists who dines at the Crown & Anchor Tavern."
- Letter to an unidentified recipient, between 1795 and 1816?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 1 page (1 leaf): autograph letter; 17 x 19 cm. (Box [83])
  Copies out a ditty--"Pretty Waltzer, Adieu!"
- Letter to an unidentified recipient, between 1795 and 1816?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 1 page (1 leaf): autograph letter; 19 x 12 cm. (Box [84])
  Piozzi suggests that her addressee will "cut a good losing Figure at the Whist Table next Monday" and offers to lend her copy of Zoonomia (by Erasmus Darwin), a book with "many very fine things in it, and many very strange ones."
  Correspondence; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821 -- Correspondence; Darwin, Erasmus, 1731-1802; Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863 -- Correspondence
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, between 1795 and 1809?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 1 page (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 24 x 19 cm. (Box [85])
  Discusses treatment of the coachman's inflamed blood with "Manna." Mr. Piozzi's health is slowly improving. People mentioned: the coachman and Mr. Piozzi.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, between 1795 and 1806?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 24 x 19 cm. (Box [86])
  Piozzi asks that Dr. Thackeray visit to attend to her "little delicate Maid" who has a "stomach case" and discusses its cause and treatment. People mentioned: Piozzi's maid, Mr. Moore, Sir Lucas Pepys, Mrs. Piozzi's eldest daughter, Allen, and Mr. Piozzi.
- Letter to an unidentified recipient, between 1795 and 1816?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 1 page (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [87])
  Piozzi writes, "the Frolicks Dear Sir have been blown away by the Wind & starved in the Snow--not so the Dinner at which we hope to see you."
- Letter to an unidentified recipient, between 1795 and 1816?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 1 page (1 leaf): autograph letter; 17 x 19 cm. (Box [88])
  Piozzi sends the recipient her old letters and writes, "the Prophet's Mess of Blasphemy & Madness is at Mrs. Heaton's." People mentioned: Mrs. Heaton.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, between 1795 and 1816?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 1 page (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 12 x 20 cm. (Box [89])
  Piozzi asks Dr. Thackeray to treat the "Gardiner" [sic], who is ill and "bent on quackery." She wishes "to hinder any Harm coming to a valuable Servant." People mentioned: "the Gardiner."
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, between 1795 and 1806?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 1 page (1 leaf): autograph letter; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [90])
  Piozzi invites Thackeray to dinner with Count Grimani and asks him assist her daughter in showing the Count the Lleweni Bleach Works. People mentioned: Count Grimani and Cecilia (Piozzi's daughter).
  Correspondence; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821 -- Correspondence; Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863 -- Correspondence; Grimani, Filippo Vincenzi, 1755-1826; Mostyn, Cecilia Margaretta Thrale, 1777-1857
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, between 1795 and 1806?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 1 page (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 12 x 19 cm. (Box [91])
  Piozzi writes that the rector sent her sick husband a woodcock for dinner, but she won't tell him about it until she learns from Thackeray whether he may eat it. Unlike Eve who "did tempt her unlucky Partner to eat forbidden food," Piozzi remains obedient to the Doctor's instructions. People mentioned: the rector, Mr. Piozzi, and Eve.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, between 1795 and 1806?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 1 page (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 26 x 20 cm. (Box [92])
  Mr. Piozzi is ill "with Agony like a Woman in Labour." Mrs. Piozzi asks Thackeray to come to make sure "there is no Danger." People mentioned: Mr. Piozzi and Mr. Moore.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, between 1795 and 1806?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (2 leaves): autograph letter; 21 x 16 cm. (Box [93])
  Discusses household illnesses and treatments.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, between 1795 and 1806? Easter Sunday; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 1 page (1 leaf): autograph letter; 24 x 19 cm. (Box [94])
  Mrs. Piozzi's tongue is swollen and discolored after eating a China Orange. She begs Dr. Thackeray's advice. People mentioned: Mr. Piozzi.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1795?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 1 page (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [95])
  Mr. Piozzi thinks he may have gout. Mrs. Piozzi hopes it is "nothing at all." People mentioned: Mr. Piozzi.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, between 1795 and 1816?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 1 page (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 20 x 16 cm. (Box [96])
  Petronilla (i.e., Maria Stella Petronilla Chiappini?) is ill and Piozzi requests Thackeray's medical advice. People mentioned: Petronilla and "the Boys."
  Correspondence; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821 -- Correspondence; Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863 -- Correspondence; Ungern-Sternberg, Maria Stella Petronilla, Baroness, 1773-1843
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, between 1795 and 1806?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 1 page (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 10 x 19 cm. (Box [97])
  Mr. Piozzi's gout alarms him and Mrs. Piozzi wonders what she should do. People mentioned: Mr. Piozzi and Mr. Moore.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, between 1795 and 1806?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 1 page (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 18 cm. (Box [98])
  Piozzi asks Thackeray not to forget his promise to visit. She writes that if he does, "Mr. Piozzi promises to walk to the Dining Parlour to meet" him. It will be Mr. Piozzi's "first Attempt for 14 Weeks." People mentioned: Mr. Piozzi.